Mohamed Bana

London, UK and Marrakech, Morocco



in linkedin.com/in/mbana



m@bana.io



https://bana.io/cv



+212624846935

Summary

Contact details at the end.

Please, ONLY contact me about remote roles that meet these conditions:

- * Golang/Go roles.
- * Vue.js roles.
- * I am up for learning more of Rust. It's just a hobby at the moment.
- * Roles where Linux, Google Cloud Platform or Azure, Docker and Open Banking are being used.

I kindly request that you respect my requests and do not spam me about roles that don't fit these criteria.

I am a well-rounded Software Engineer, and I understand what it takes to release a product having worked on the back-end, front-end, testing and finally the deployment aspect of several products.

Contact Details:

- +212624846935 (Moroccan Mobile)
- +212808526830 (Moroccan Home Landline)

Experience



Full Stack Go and Vue.js Developer (contractor)

Open Banking

May 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 9 months)

Golang, Go, Vue.js Full Stack Developer working at Open Banking on a tool that will validate a bank's implementation of the OpenBanking API spec, see:

- * https://bitbucket.org/openbankingteam/conformance-suite
- * https://hub.docker.com/u/openbanking/

Tech: Go, Golang, Node.js, Vue.js, Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, Kompose, CircleCI, Swagger, WebSocket, Elixir, Bitbucket Pipelines.

Senior Engineer (contractor)

Ninety Percent of Everything

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018 (3 months)

Worked at startup specialising in software that runs on ship on two projects that were heavily Go-based.

Tech: Go, gRPC, Protocol Buffers, MongoDB, GraphQL, go gorilla/mux, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, NodeJS, Jest, Concourse CI, Postgres.



Full Stack Developer (contractor)

Root Capital

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017 (3 months)

Worked as a full stack Node.js developer on the Minds for Life application, mainly on the forum.

Tech: JavaScript, ES6, Node.js, react, react-redux, react-boilerplate, Webpack, Koa, Knex.js, Sequel Pro, Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, Semaphore CI, Wercker.

Full Stack Developer (contractor)

Lloyds Banking Group

Mar 2017 - Jun 2017 (4 months)

NodeJS - JavaScript:

- * Loopback for server-side of the code.
- * ES5/6-based code base.

Monitoring/Devops:

- * Splunk and sending logs via (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syslog) a LogDrain service available on Bluemix.
- * Gerrit for managing code.

CI:

- * Jenkins: Configuring, managing and installing.
- * Jenkins 2: Same as previous plus writing pipeline scripts.

Senior Front-End Engineer

Synthace Limited

Apr 2016 - Nov 2016 (8 months)

Did a fair amount of architectural UI work.

Tech: JavaScript, ES6, Polymer, Web Components, TypeScript, VSCode, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Go, Web Component Tester, Git, Swagger.

G Developer

IG

Sep 2014 - Feb 2016 (1 year 6 months)

- * Price & Indicator Alerts: My main responsibility was handling the UI aspect—setting, configuring, triggering—of the various Alerts we support, from the basic Price Alert to Technical Indicators such as RSI and Moving Average. Tech New: Modern UI powered by ES2015 (Babel), Ember.js, Handlebars and Less. The UI was then composed of isolated and reusable Ember components. Runs on a NodeJS server, managed with npm and bower, and version controlled using Git. Integration and unit tests written in Mocha then run using Karma. Tech Old: Vanilla JavaScript using an in-house framework when changing the previous UI.
- * Charts: Assisted in the conversion of the Adobe Flex Real Time Charts to an SVG-based version. Tech: d3 and tested like above.
- * Deeplinking: A hashed action link, like typical deeplinks, that we send to our Clients which then launches the mobile IG app, or directs them to the app store for the device with the IG app pre-selected. Upon login the action is carried out automatically. I did the bulk of the work with the team lead overseeing it. Tech: Java 8, Spring and acceptance tested using Cucumber. Redirecting and launching of the IG app was done using vanilla JavaScript.

O Software Developer

ITRS Group

Feb 2010 - Sep 2014 (4 years 8 months)

3. JavaScript (UI) Developer, 01/2014-09/2014:

UI for the next generation of the product which is built around, loosely speaking, a real-time distributed analytics store.

Tech: JavaScript, NodeJS, Node-WebKit, Durandal, KnockoutJS, RequireJS, Git, Jasmine, Protractor (WebDriverJS), Jenkins, Bower, HTML5, CSS, LoopBack.io.

2. Java (UI) Developer - 07/2012-12/2013:

Worked with two developers and one QA member on a new Swing UI, ACLite.

Tech: Java, Maven, Swing, Eclipse, Jenkins, Git, Vagrant.

1. C++ Developer - 02/2010-06/2012:

Spent one year with Run The Business (RTB) team, a team set-up to fix critical bugs that Customers encounter. Prior to this I was one of three developers working in the Transactions and Latency Monitoring team (part of the backend team) doing core C++. We wrote and maintained the following plug-ins that are part of the Geneos suite:

- * FIX-Analyser: Monitors FIX (protocol) messages.
- * Feed Latency Monitor: Monitors feeds and calculates latency of instruments and fields across the monitored feeds.
- * Message Tracker: Tracks, generally, FIX messages across several checkpoints.
- * Market Data Reliability: See below. And bespoke plug-ins written for specific firms.

We also maintained several non-finance specific plug-ins. I ported another bespoke plug-in called Price Latency Monitor (provides latency figures for bonds) to MS VC++ when I worked on this team.

Projects:

- * Helped in converting the Windows version of the entire product suite from Visual Studio 2005 to 2010.
- * Helped in writing the Market Data Reliability plug-in. This plug-in connects to the Patsystem's Trading API (www.patsystems.com) to monitor commodity prices, using their C API, to determine if prices are 'stale'.
- * I ported a significant part of our product to Solaris x86-64 (64-bit non-sparc architecture).

Tech: C++, STL, Boost, Visual Studio, Linux/Unix, GDB, DBX, Make, Configure, XML, XPath, CPPUnit.



Tester

Thomson Reuters

Sep 2009 - Nov 2009 (3 months)

User Acceptance Testing of the latest release of Thomson Reuter's 3000 extra, then called UTAH, now called Eikon.



Software Developer Intern

Thomson Reuters

May 2009 - Sep 2009 (5 months)

One of four developers working on a search and navigation interface to Global Product Search.

Languages/Technologies: C#, Silverlight 3.0, MS SQL Server 2005, LINQ, Web Services (WCF), XML and Visual Studio 2008. CruiseControl.NET.

Education



A City, University of London

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2005 - 2008



London Business School

CSEL, Trading and Market Structure 2008 - 2009



UCL

Master of Science - MS, Software Systems Engineering 2008 - 2009

Skills

Golang • Full-Stack Development • Vue.js • Software Development • Linux • JavaScript • Node.js • Git • Google Cloud Platform • Docker